Guide to the Ann Cornelisen Papers, 1714-1994 (bulk 1954-1990)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Ann Cornelisen Papers
1714-1994
1954-1990
Cornelisen, Ann, 1926-
20 cubic feet (50 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, manuscripts, research material, as well as audio-visual material relating to the life and work of Ann Cornelisen, writer and photographer.
Biographical Note
Ann Cornelisen is best known as the author of several books detailing the landscape and culture of southern Italy. She first went to Italy in 1954 with plans of studying archaeology in Rome. However, after meeting Giovanna "Gianna" Thompson, a representative of the British Save the Children Fund, the course of her life was forever changed. She traveled with Gianna to many small, impoverished towns in central and southern Italy documenting her experiences in her journals, letters home, and on film. She eventually made Ortona in the Abruzzo region her permanent home, but spent much of her time studying the town of Tricarico in Basilicata, which was the focus of her first book, Torregreca. Cornelisen spent the rest of her professional career in Italy and published three more nonfiction books about the country as well as two novels.
More biographical information is available in her books, but also in the Biography series of this collection and in the reference work, Contemporary Authors, volume 144 (Ref PN451 .C66).
Chronology
12 Nov 1926 Born in Cleveland, Ohio
1944-1946 Studied at Vassar College
1944 Made her debut into Chicago society
7 Feb 1953 Married Gordon Carpenter O'Gara
1954 First trip to Italy
27 Nov 1957 Married Charles Walker Cammack III
1974 Special award, National Institute of Arts and Letters
1974 American Academy Award in literature
1977 Guggenheim fellowship
1979 Indiana University, Patten Foundation Lecturer
1980 Christopher Award
12 Nov 2003 Died in Rome, Georgia
Publications
1969 Torregreca: Life, Death, Miracles. Little, Brown: Boston, MA (reprinted in 2002 by Steerforth Italia: South Royalton, VT).
1971 Vendetta of Silence. Little, Brown: Boston, MA.
1976 Women of the Shadows. Little, Brown: Boston, MA (reprinted in 2001 as Women of the Shadows: Wives and Mothers of Southern Italy, Steerforth Italia: South Royalton, VT).
1980 Strangers and Pilgrims: The Last Italian Migration, Holt: New York, NY (published in London, England as Flight from Torregreca, Macmillan, 1980).
1983 Any Four Women Could Rob the Bank of Italy. Holt: New York, NY.
1990 Where It All Began: Italy, 1954. Dutton: New York, NY.
Scope and Content Note
The Ann Cornelisen collection includes correspondence, manuscripts, research material, as well as audio-visual material such as postcards, maps, photographic prints, slides, negatives and audiotapes. Although there is material from her young life in Chicago and her student years at Vassar, the bulk of the collection relates to her time in Italy. Of particular note is the correspondence to her parents. Cornelisen wrote to her parents several times per week, chronicling her experiences in Italy and other parts of Europe; thus, the correspondence serves as a kind of journal. The manuscripts in the "Writings" series document her process as both a fiction and non-fiction writer, and include much unpublished material. The photographic material, much never published or exhibited, is particularly significant because of the artistic merit of the images and the detail with which she documented life in mid-century Southern Italy.
Access
The audio material in this collection is restricted due to fragility. Please contact the staff for further information. The remainder of the collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Save the Children Fund (Great Britain)
Subjects:
Authors, American--20th century--Homes and haunts--Italy; Photography--Italy; Women authors, American--20th century; Women photographers; Women--Italy, Southern
Places:
Italy, Southern--Social conditions; Italy, Southern--Social life and customs; Ortona (Italy)--Social life and customs; Italy, Southern--Description and travel; Tricarico (Italy)--Description and travel; Rome (Italy)--Description and travel; Ortona (Italy)--Description and travel
VCL Categories
Literature and Writing; Travel
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, May 2007.
Acquisition Information
Bequeathed by Ann Cornelisen in 2004.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual material may require special viewers/players.
Series List
- Series I. Biography, 1943-1991, n.d.; (Boxes 6, 7, 20, 21, and 29)
  This series consists of three versions of one "diary" dating from 1959-1960, news clippings, date and address books and financial information. It also includes two scrapbooks. One, from 1943-1945 includes photographs and clippings relating to her debut into Chicago society and other aspects of her young social life. The other, from 1947-1951, includes photographs and clippings relating to the Junior League and her other civic work.
- Series II. Correspondence, 1943-1994, n.d.; (Boxes 1 and 2)
  This series includes both personal and professional correspondence. By far the largest cache of letters are to Cornelisen's parents. She wrote several times per week throughout most of her life in Europe. Other significant correspondents include her editor, William "Billy" Abrahams and her agent, Cyrilly Abels. There are also letters from her friend Giovanna "Gianna" Thompson and a few letters from one of the main subjects of her writings, Chichella.
- Series III. Writings, 1954-1991, n.d.; (Boxes 3-6 and 29)
  The Writings series consists of drafts, notes, and reviews of Cornelisen's books, articles and short stories. The material that best depicts the editing process is that relating to Any Four Women Could Rob the Bank of Italy, her mystery/adventure novel. There are also a number of published reviews of other writers' work in the series. The research material in this series includes translated transcripts of interviews with Chichella. The audio reels of these interviews are in Series VII.
  IIIa. Books
  IIIb. Articles and Short Stories
  IIIc. Reviews by Ann Cornelisen
  IIId. Research Material and Notes
  IIIe. Miscellaneous
- Series IV. Photographs, 1941-1990, n.d.; (Boxes 8-17, 22, 24-28 and 30-50)
  This series includes four kinds of photographic material: prints, contact sheets and prints, slides, and negatives.
  IVa. Prints: The prints are nearly all black and white, but are a variety of sizes, ranging from 3x5 inch snaps to 20x 25 inch mounted exhibit prints. They are physically organized by size, and intellectually divided into two broad categories: personal and professional. Within those categories, the envelopes and folders are generally described using terms gleaned by the archivist. In a few cases, Cornelisen actually labeled the original enclosures or the prints; these items can be identified by quotation marks around the folder titles.
  IVb. Negatives: There are 35mm and 120mm negatives in this series. The bulk of them are numbered but otherwise unlabeled. Others were not numbered, but the archivist continued the numbering system in order to maintain original order. This artifical numbering begins with [No. 176]. See the prints, contact sheets and contact prints in boxes 13, 14 and 50 for positive images from some of the negatives.
  IVc. Contact Sheets and Contact Prints: The majority of the contact sheets were in numbered envelopes, but otherwise unlabeled. The subject matter is Italy, but no other information is currently available. The contact prints were originally housed with the negatives. Most of the prints are from the section of negatives that were not numbered and so were assigned a number by the archivist.
  IVd. Slides: Originally, there were 43 plastic containers, two loose piles and one metal box of slides. Only four of the plastic containers had any indication of their content. Because the slides needed to be rehoused for preservation purposes, the only means of maintaining any original order was to sort slide boxes by style and assume that they came from roughly the same time period. Thus, the container number was supplied by the archivist and does not necessarily reflect any organizational structure used by Cornelisen. The slides in the metal box were also rehoused. This box included a list of subjects, but it is difficult to see how the list matches the slides. The list is housed in the box with those slides.
- Series V. Postcards, 1954-1986; (Boxes 18 and 19)
  Cornelisen saved most of her postcards separately from her other correspondence, roughly organized by country and region. Some are blank, some she sent to her parents, and some came from other friends from Italy and elsewhere. Photocopies of the message side of these postcards have been filed with her correspondence.
- Series VI. Maps and Posters, 1714-1980, n.d.; (Box 29 and map case)
  This series includes five maps of Italy and several posters. One map is a modern map Cornelisen probably used in lectures, but the other maps seem to date from the 18th century.
- Series VII. Audio Tapes, 1963-1969, n.d.; (Box 23)
  Includes 24 reels ranging from 3 to 7 inches. The original box was labeled "Original Chichella tapes made in 1963-64 with AC." These are numbered 1-12, with reels 5 and 10 missing. There are also other reels, labeled "Ferrarotti," "Jimmy Crosse" and "Folk Songs - Tuscany." Several of the 5 inch reels have no identifying information and may be blank. The 7 inch reels say they have been erased.
Container List
- Series I. Biography
  - Scrapbook, 1943-1945 (Box 20)
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1951 (Box 21)
  - Diary, 1959-1960 (7.1)
  - Diary, 1959-1960 (7.2)
  - Diary, 1960 (7.3)
  - News Clippings (photocopies), 1943-1971, n.d. (7.4)
  - Date and Address books, 1957, 1959, 1966 (7.5)
  - News Clippings (originals), 1943-1957, n.d. (7.6)
  - News Clippings (originals), 1945-1957 (29.3)
  - News Clippings (originals), 1971 (29.6)
  - Finances - Account Book (6.39)
  - Finances - House in Cortona, ca 1972-1991 (6.40)
  - Finances - Insurance and accidents, 1964-1968 (6.41)
  - Finances – Insurance, 1972-1989 (6.42)
  - Finances - Royalty Statements and Contracts (6.43)
  - Finances - Banking, Investments, and Finances (6.44)
  - Finances - Miscellaneous Bills and Receipts (6.45)
  - Miscellaneous (7.7)
  - Miscellaneous (7.7)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Abels, Cyrilly [Literary Agent], 1968-1970 (1.1)
  - Abels, Cyrilly [Literary Agent], 1971-1975 (1.2)
  - Abrahams, William "Billy,", 1966-1968 (1.3)
  - Abrahams, William "Billy,", 1969-1972 (1.4)
  - Abrahams, William "Billy,", 1973-1975 (1.5)
  - Abrahams, William "Billy,", 1976-1990 (1.6)
  - Adams, Alice, 1972-1980 (1.7)
  - Atlantic Monthly Press; see also Abrahams, William "Billy,", 1968-1970 (1.8)
  - Atlantic Monthly Press; see also Davison, Jane & Peter; see also Abrahams, William "Billy,", 1971 (1.9)
  - Atlantic Monthly Press; see also Abrahams, William "Billy,", 1972-1977 (1.10)
  - Bailey, Paul, 1980 (1.11)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1974, 1975 (1.12)
  - Byrne, Moyra, 1990-1993 (1.13)
  - Caporale, Rocco, 1977-1990 (1.14)
  - Coles, Robert, 1970-1979 (1.15)
  - Cornelisen, Ydoine and Ralph, circa 1954 (1.16)
  - Cornelisen, Ydoine and Ralph, 1955-1965 (1.17 - 1.34)
  - Cornelisen, Ydoine and Ralph, 1966-1987 (2.1 - 2.24)
  - Cornelisen, Ydoine and Ralph, undated (2.25)
  - from Ydoine and Ralph Cornelisen, 1966 (2.26)
  - Letters to Ydoine and Ralph Cornelisen from others, 1954-1971 (2.27)
  - To "Young Man,", 1960, 1961, undated (2.28)
  - Davison, Jane and Peter; see also Atlantic Monthly Press for Peter Davison, 1977-1981 (2.29)
  - Guggenheim Foundation Fellowship, 1975-1979 (2.30)
  - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, 1983 (2.31)
  - Indiana University, 1978-1979 (2.32)
  - Kanon, Joseph and Robin Straus, 1969-1986 (2.33)
  - Life Magazine, 1968-1969 (2.34)
  - Macmillan, 1968-1989 (2.35)
  - Musacchio, Aldo, 1970-1975 (2.36)
  - Patete, Nancy Fioritto Piazza, 1978-1980 (2.55)
  - Random House, 1976-1977 (2.37)
  - Save the Children Fund, 1955-1969 (2.38)
  - Siebert, Renate, 1993 (2.39)
  - Smith, Liz, 1977-1978 (2.40)
  - Talese, Gay, 1982 (2.41)
  - Thompson, Giovanna "Gianna"; see also Save the Children Fund, 1955 (2.42)
  - Thompson, Giovanna "Gianna,", 1957 (2.43)
  - Thompson, Giovanna "Gianna,", 1958-1959, 1985 (2.44)
  - Vassar College, 1943-1994 (2.45)
  - Wallace Literary Agency, 1984-1990 (2.46)
  - Miscellaneous Personal, 1952-1969 (2.47)
  - Miscellaneous Personal, 1969-1993, undated (2.48)
  - Miscellaneous Official, circa 1954-1974 (2.49)
  - Miscellaneous Official, 1975-1989 (2.50)
  - Miscellaneous Official, 1990-1994 (2.51)
  - Miscellaneous Fan Mail, 1976-1991 (2.52)
  - "Anne,", 1975, 1979 (2.53)
  - Chichella, 1969 (2.54)
- Series III. Writings
  - Books
    - First Book Attempt
      - First Version, ca 1958 (3.1)
      - Second Version, ca 1958 (3.2)
      - Another Version, 1958-1959 (3.3)
    - Torregreca
      - Early Draft, entitled "Chichella" pp. 1-201 (3.4)
      - Early Draft, entitled "Chichella" pp. 202-end (3.5)
      - Early Draft, entitled "Chichella and the Torregreca Way," pp. 1-78, 1965 (3.6)
      - Early Draft, entitled "Chichella and the Torregreca Way," pp. 79-end, 1965 (3.7)
      - Early Draft, entitled "Chichella, Vol. II,", 1966 (3.8)
      - Clean Typescript, pp. 1-52, 1968 (3.9)
      - Clean Typescript, pp. 53-150, 1968 (3.10)
      - Clean Typescript, pp. 151-241, 1968 (3.11)
      - Clean Typescript, pp. 242-end, 1968 (3.12)
      - Reviews, 1969 (3.13)
      - Italian Translation Drafts (3.14)
      - Correspondence, ca 1970 (3.15)
      - Miscellaneous (3.16)
    - Vendetta of Silence
      - Draft, entitled "The S. B. Notebooks,", 1970 (3.17)
      - Reviews (3.18)
    - Women of the Shadows
      - Early Draft # 1, ca 1975 (3.19)
      - Early Draft # 2 (3.20)
      - "Ninetta," Television Adaptation, ca 1975-1980 (3.21)
      - Italian Translation, partial, 1980 (3.22)
      - Reviews (3.23)
      - Reviews - New York Times, 1976 (29.1)
    - Strangers and Pilgrims
      - Early Draft, pp. 1-89 (3.24)
      - Early Draft - Additional Pages and Fragmentary Chapters (3.25)
      - Typescript, pp. 1-194, ca 1979 (3.26)
      - Typescript, pp. 195-335, ca 1979 (4.1)
      - Typescript, pp. 336-end, ca 1979 (4.2)
      - "Notes on Those Who Have Emigrated" (4.3)
      - Miscellaneous Notes and Correspondence (4.4)
      - Reviews (4.5)
    - Any Four Women Could Rob the Bank of Italy
      - First Draft, entitled, "Soon to be a Major Motion Picture," pp. 1-74 (4.6)
      - First Draft, entitled, "Soon to be a Major Motion Picture," pp. 75-end (4.7)
      - Early Draft, entitled, "The Great Tuscan Train Robbery…" pp. 1-65 (4.8)
      - Early Draft, entitled, "The Great Tuscan Train Robbery…" pp. 66-119 (4.9)
      - Early Draft, entitled, "The Great Tuscan Train Robbery…" pp. 120- end (4.10)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 1 of 8 (4.11)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 2 of 8 (4.12)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 3 of 8 (4.13)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 4 of 8 (4.14)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 5 of 8 (4.15)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 6 of 8 (4.16)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 7 of 8 (4.17)
      - Early Draft Fragments, folder 8 of 8 (4.18)
      - Partial Draft, including breakdown of the Robbery, Nov. 1979 (4.19)
      - Partial Draft, pp. 1-96, Aug 1982 (4.20)
      - Partial Draft, pp. 97-181, Aug 1982 (4.21)
      - Partial Draft, pp. 182-200 and fragments, Aug 1982 (4.22)
      - Partial Draft, 154-316 (4.23)
      - Edited Draft, pp. 1-134 (4.24)
      - Edited Draft, pp. 135-end (4.25)
      - Semi Final Draft, pp. 1-97 (4.26)
      - Semi Final Draft, pp. 98-199 (4.27)
      - Semi Final Draft, pp. 200- end (4.28)
      - Final Manuscript, pp. 1-114, Jan 1983 (5.1)
      - Final Manuscript, pp. 115-225, Jan 1983 (5.2)
      - Final Manuscript, pp. 226-end, Jan 1983 (5.3)
      - Reviews, 1984 (5.4)
      - Notes, ca 1980 (5.5)
      - Miscellaneous (5.6)
    - Where It All Began
      - Typescript, pp. 1-128, ca 1989 (5.7)
      - Typescript, pp. 129-269, ca 1989 (5.8)
      - Typescript, pp. 270-end, ca 1989 (5.9)
      - Partial draft (5.10)
      - Draft (5.11)
      - Drafts and Notes, folder 1 of 5 (5.12)
      - Drafts and Notes, folder 2 of 5 (5.13)
      - Drafts and Notes, folder 3 of 5 (5.14)
      - Drafts and Notes, folder 4 of 4 (5.15)
      - Drafts and Notes, folder 5 of 5 (5.16)
      - Draft Fragments (5.17)
      - Correspondence (5.18)
      - Editing Notes, 1989 (5.19)
      - Reviews (5.20)
  - Articles and Short Stories
    - "The Other Italy," Vassar Alumnae Magazine, Dec 1966 (5.21)
    - "Prophesies, Witches, and Spells," Atlantic, Aug 1968 (5.22)
    - "Life Under Glass,", 1968 (5.23)
    - "Our Friend Pasquale," Atlantic, Oct 1969 (5.24)
    - "The Night Antonio was Born,", ca 1969 (5.25)
    - "Chichella: She was My Friend…" MS, Feb 1978 (5.26)
    - "A Landscape to Soothe the Heart," New York Times Magazine, 1985 (5.27)
    - "Chichella Fascide," obituary, 1986 (5.28)
    - "The Apricot House" (5.29)
    - "Casa DiMaio"- first draft (5.30)
    - "Casa DiMaio"- correspondence and notes, 1969-1975 (5.31)
    - "Festas" (5.32)
    - "Festas" (5.33)
    - "Festas"-fragments of drafts from a folder labeled "Festas" (5.34)
    - "Journey in Egypt" (5.35)
    - "The Manifestation" (5.36)
    - Miscellaneous News Articles, 1956, 1971 (29.5)
  - Reviews by A. C.
    - A Traveler in Southern Italy by H.V. Morton, 1969 (6.1)
    - Fenwomen by Mary Chamberlain, 1975 (6.2)
    - Folklore by the Fireside by Alessandro Falassi, 1980 (6.3)
    - Pioneer Women by Joanna Stratton, 1981 (6.4)
    - Spello by John and Adeline Hartcup, 1986 (6.5)
    - Within the Labyrinth by Norman Lewis, 1986 (6.6)
    - On Persephone’s Island by Mary Taylor Simeti, 1986 (6.7)
    - Democracy Italian Style by Joseph Palonbasa, 1987 (6.8)
    - The City and the House by Natalie Ginzberg, 1987 (6.9)
    - Summer’s Lease by John Mortimer, 1988 (6.10)
    - The Lost Father by Marina Warner, 1989 (6.11)
    - The South by Colm Toibin, 1991 (6.12)
  - Research Material and Notes
    - Chichella Tape Transcripts, Folder 1 (6.13)
    - Chichella Tape Transcripts, Folder 2 (6.14)
    - Chichella Notes (6.15)
    - Miscellaneous Notes from Lucania and Tricarico, ca 1954-1971 (6.16)
    - Ortona Notes - used or rejected (6.17)
    - Abruzzo Notes, 1958 (6.18)
    - Abruzzo Notes, ca 1964 (6.19)
    - Montes Family Research Summary, 1970-1971 (6.20)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Reports [for Save the Children?], 1958 (6.21)
    - Lecture Notes, 1958-1990 (6.22)
    - Lecture Notes - note cards, n.d. (6.23)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (6.24)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (6.25)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (6.26)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (6.27)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (6.28)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (6.29)
    - Miscellaneous Reviews, Notes and Clippings (6.30)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments, ca 1969 (6.31)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments (6.32)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments (6.33)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments (6.34)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments (6.35)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments (6.36)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments - "Introduction" re Chichella (6.37)
    - Unidentified Drafts and Fragments (6.38)
- Series IV Photographs
  - Prints
    - Personal
      - Photo Wallet (8.1)
      - Portrait - Childhood (8.2)
      - Portrait at Rio Blanco Ranch, 1941 (8.29)
      - Portrait at Rio Blanco Ranch, 1941 (22.1)
      - Portrait, Debut, 1944 (22.2)
      - Portrait from Book signing, 1969 (8.3)
      - Portrait from Book signing, 1969 (8.30)
      - Portrait for San Francisco Examiner, 1975 or 1976 (8.31)
      - Photo shoot of A.C., circa 1980 (8.4)
      - Photo shoot of A.C., circa 1980 (8.5)
      - Portrait, circa 1980s (8.6)
      - Miscellaneous candids of A.C. (8.7)
      - Miscellaneous candids of A.C. (8.8)
      - Miscellaneous candids of A.C. (8.9)
      - Miscellaneous candids of A.C. (8.32)
      - Family (8.10)
      - Family (8.11)
      - Family (8.33)
      - Family (8.34)
      - Family - Father, with negatives (8.12)
      - Unidentified Family photo (22.3)
      - Unidentified Family photos (22.4)
      - Dogs (8.13)
      - Homes (8.14)
      - Homes (8.15)
      - Homes (8.16)
      - Homes (8.17)
      - Gianna Thompson (8.18)
      - From envelope labeled "W.N. - W.M.B. - P.S.," possibly of Billy Abrahams (8.19)
      - Car named "Louisa,", 1960 (8.20)
      - Cruise, circa 1957 (8.21)
      - Miscellaneous (8.22)
      - Miscellaneous (8.23)
      - Miscellaneous (8.24)
      - Miscellaneous (8.35)
      - Miscellaneous (8.36)
      - Miscellaneous (8.37)
    - Professional
      - Tricarico - Town Views (10.1)
      - Tricarico - Town Views (10.2)
      - Tricarico - Chichella (10.3)
      - Tricarico - Chichella (8.38)
      - Tricarico - Save the Children Fund Nursery, 1959, n.d. (10.4)
      - Tricarico - Save the Children Fund Nursery, 1961, n.d. (10.5)
      - "Tricarico" - Save the Children Christmas Party (10.6)
      - "Tricarico" - Children (10.7)
      - "Tricarico" - Children (10.8)
      - "Tricarico" - "Nuns" (10.9)
      - "Tricarico" – Nuns, 1960, n.d. (10.10)
      - "Tricarico" - Nuns (10.11)
      - Tricarico - "Nuns,", 1960, n.d. (10.12)
      - Tricarico - "Nuns,", 1967, n.d. (8.41)
      - Tricarico – Funeral, 1967 (10.13)
      - Tricarico - Religious Ceremony, 1959 (10.14)
      - Tricarico - Religious Ceremony, 1964 (10.15)
      - Tricarico - Festival of the Madonna, 1967, n.d. (10.16)
      - Tricarico - Festival of the Madonna, 1967 (8.39)
      - Tricarico - Festa San Pancrazio, 1967 (8.40)
      - Tricarico - Unidentified Festival (10.17)
      - "Tricarico" - Frieze (10.18)
      - "Tricarico" - Kitchen and Field Scene, 1959 (10.19)
      - "Tricarico - Old" (10.20)
      - Tricarico - "Old People,", 1967 (9.1)
      - Tricarico - Identified Individuals (9.2)
      - Tricarico – Miscellaneous, 1967, n.d. (9.3)
      - Tricarico – Miscellaneous, 1967, n.d. (9.4)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.21)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.22)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.23)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.24)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.25)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.26)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.27)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.28)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.29)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.30)
      - "Tricarico" - Miscellaneous (10.31)
      - Tricarico - Miscellaneous (10.32)
      - Tricarico? (10.33)
      - "Barrafranca, Sicily" (11.1)
      - "Castel di Sangro" (11.2)
      - "Chieti" - Orphanage (11.3)
      - "Chieti" - Orphanage (11.4)
      - "Chieti" - Orphanage (11.5)
      - "Chieti" - Orphanage (11.6)
      - "Chieti" - Miscellaneous (11.7)
      - "Ezzito,", circa 1959 (11.8)
      - "Ezzito,", circa 1959 (11.9)
      - "Ezzito,", circa 1959 (11.10)
      - "Ezzito,", circa 1959 (11.11)
      - "Ezzito,", circa 1959 (11.12)
      - "Old Woman Ezzito '59" (includes negative), 1959 (11.13)
      - "Matera,", 1955 (11.14)
      - "Naples," (11.15)
      - Ortona - Save the Children Fund Nursery, circa 1956 (11.16)
      - Ortona - Save the Children Fund Nursery, 1956 (11.17)
      - Ortona - Save the Children Fund Event (11.18)
      - Ortona – Children, 1956 (11.19)
      - Ortona - Festa of St. Thomas, 1956 (11.20)
      - Ortona – Ceramics, 1956 (11.21)
      - Ortona – Miscellaneous, circa 1956 (11.22)
      - Pietransieri, 1956 (11.23)
      - "Roccanova" - Festival (11.24)